["The Chosen Idiots"]
[Note: Parody of Dragon Quest
IV Ch. 5 title "The Chosen."]
あれが たま様のﾒｲﾝｼｽﾃﾑだ｡
That's Lady Tama's main system.
すでにｳｲﾙｽに深く侵食され
ﾔﾂらの牙城と化している｡
It's already been taken over by the viruses
and converted into their stronghold.
あれに巣食い
獏たちのﾒｲﾝﾌﾞﾚｲﾝとなり➡
The brains behind the Tapir
and their extensive invasion
獏を生み出し続けるのが獏大魔王｡
dwell inside-the Archfiend Tapir.
たま様の体内中に広がる
獏たちの雛形｡
The progenitor of all the Tapir spreading
throughout Lady Tama's body.
獏たちの王だ｡
The king of the Tapir.
ﾔﾂを駆除しなければ
獏たちの侵略は止まらない｡
We won't be able to stop the Tapir
invasion unless we destroy him.
世界に平和を取り戻すには
たま様を救うには➡
To return peace to this world...
To save Lady Tama...
ﾔﾂを倒すしかない｡
We must defeat him.
The Archfiend Tapir is like the
main system for the Tapir.
(たま)獏大魔王は 獏たちにとって
ﾒｲﾝｼｽﾃﾑのようなものです｡
彼を駆除すれば
すべての獏も無力化するはずです｡
Destroying him should render
the Tapir powerless.
(新八)問題は どうやって
獏大魔王の元まで➡
The problem is how we're going
to reach the Archfiend Tapir.
たどり着くかですね｡
As you would expect of the
enemy's main base...
さすがは敵の本拠地｡
黒ﾀｲﾂ一色ですよ｡
Black bodysuits everywhere you look.
(神楽)おまけに みんな
前戦ったﾔﾂより➡
And they all look stronger than
the ones we've fought before.
強そうなのばっかりｱﾙよ｡
This is the Archfiend Tapir's territory.
The place is swarming with the latest viruses
created by the Archfiend Tapir.
They won't be easy to defeat like before.
We'll need to come up with a plan.
Come on now.
(銀時)おいおい
勘弁してくれよ｡
Give me a break.
Why slow down after coming this far?
ここまで来て
まどろっこしいんだよ｡
最新型っつったって どうせ
ｺｲﾂのﾄﾞﾗｸｴ脳を食って進化した➡
Those new viruses are just pseudo
DQ characters that spawned from
ﾄﾞﾗｸｴごっこしかできねえ
ﾊﾞｶどもだろ｡ ｺｲﾂと同じで｡
the virus eating her DQ-crazed brain.
Like this guy.
作戦なんていらねえよ｡
こんなﾔﾂら相手に｡
We don't need a plan to
deal with these freaks.
ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝいこうぜ｡
待ていっ！
Just go on a rampage.
Wait!
魔王の根城を前に
ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝいこうぜなど➡
Only the most foolish of fools
would suggest "rampaging"
愚策中の愚策｡
straight into the Archfiend
Tapir's stronghold!
A party with you as its leader would run
out of MP before reaching the Archfiend
ｷｻﾏのようなﾔﾂが率いるﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰが➡
魔王にたどり着く前に
ＭＰを使いきり➡
魔王になにもできず
長ったらしい復活の呪文を➡
and be forced to jot down a long resurrection
spell to even make it halfway there.
[Note: Parody of Dragon Quest III.]
ﾒﾓるﾊﾒになるんだ｡
あぁ ばっちい｡
What an idiot.
ｷｻﾏの指示で動いていたら
ﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰは全滅だ｡
The party would be wiped out
if we followed your orders!
たま様を救う勇者は このｵﾚ｡
I am the hero who will save Lady Tama.
遊び人は ﾙｲｰﾀﾞの酒場で
飲んだくれているがいい｡
A Jester like you should go
goof off in Luida's bar!
[Note: Parody of Jester class and Luida
character from Dragon Quest III.]
誰が遊び人だ ｺﾗ！
Who are you calling a Jester, damn it?!
Sure, I might goof off!
確かにｵﾚは遊び人かもしれない｡
だが ｵﾚとﾋﾞｱﾝｶの息子は➡
But the son of Bianca and I will
become the Heavenly Hero!
[Note: Parody of "Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride." Bianca is one of two women whom the player can choose for the hero to marry.]
天空の勇者になるからね｡
ただの遊び人じゃないからね｡
So I'm no ordinary Jester!
天空の遊び人だからね｡
I'm the Heavenly Jester!
It would be best to avoid combat
魔王にたどり着くまでは
ﾑﾀﾞな戦闘は避け➡
before we reach the Archfiend
and conserve our health.
体力を温存したほうがいい｡
回復も薬草でなんとかしのごう｡
Use herbs to heal.
おい 聞いてんのか ｺｽﾌﾟﾚ野郎！
Hey! You listening to me, cosplay freak?!
We'll go with a "no magic" tactic.
作戦は ｢呪文は使うな｣で｡
いや ﾊﾅからﾎﾞｸら
呪文なんて使えないんですけど｡
Uh, we don't have any
magic to begin with.
そんな消極的な策で
魔王に勝てるわけねえだろ｡
How can we defeat the Archfiend
with such a conservative tactic?
ﾊﾞｶか ｵﾒｴは！
Are you an idiot?
A stingy party led by you would
carry so many herbs
ｵﾒｴみてえなｹﾁなﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰが➡
you wouldn't be able to open
any treasure chests
薬草持ちすぎて
宝箱もろくに開けられず➡
魔王にたどり着く前に
ＭＰ満ﾀﾝのまま全滅すんだよ｡
and get wiped out with full MP before
you even reach the Archfiend.
ここは ｢ｸﾘﾌﾄ以外ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝいこうぜ｣
でいこう｡
We should all use "Firevolt"
except for Kiryl.
[Note: Firevolt is a powerful spell.
Kiryl is a priest from Dragon Quest IV.]
I've never heard of that tactic!
聞いたことねえけど そんな作戦｡
ｸﾘﾌﾄって誰よ？
Who's Kiryl?!
ｸﾘﾌﾄは ほっとくと
魔王にまでｻﾞﾗｷをかける➡
Kiryl is the Shinpachi-like character
that stupidly casts Defeat
[Note: The Defeat spell one-hit kills enemies. Useless on bosses. Kiryl (aka Cristo) tried this spell on Archfiend in Dragon Quest IV.]
on the Archfiend if you leave
him to his own devices.
新八的ﾎﾟｼﾞｼｮﾝだ｡
It's better to keep him silenced.
黙ってたほうがいい｡
役立たずって言ってんの それ？
Are you trying to say I'm useless?
ｸﾘﾌﾄも使いこなせないとは笑止｡
You don't even know how to use
Kiryl properly? Laughable.
やはり
ｷｻﾏにﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰを率いる資格はない｡
It appears that you are unqualified
to lead this party.
黙っとけ｡ ﾃﾒｴもｸﾘﾌﾄとﾌﾞﾗｲと
ﾄﾙﾈｺと一緒に➡
Shut up.
You wanna live on a cart with
Kiryl, Borya, and Torneko?
馬車で暮らしてえのか｡
ﾍﾞｽﾄﾒﾝﾊﾞｰの陰口だけが生きがいの
暗い生活を送りてえのか？
Wanna live a gloomy life badmouthing
the best members behind their backs?
また始まっちゃったよ｡
ﾀﾞﾒだ この２人｡
There they go again.
The two of them are hopeless.
たま なんとかしてよ｡
Tama, do something.
Understood.
Then we'll compromise and go with "Keep
everyone except Kiryl healed up."
You want Kiryl to die?!
ｸﾘﾌﾄ死ねってか！
それﾎﾞｸに言ってんですか？
Was that directed at me?!
そんなにﾎﾞｸは役に立ちませんか！
Am I that useless?!
Whatever then. We'll go with that.
しかたねえな｡
じゃあ それでいこう｡
｢ｸﾘﾌﾄにｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝいこうぜ｣で｡
Firevolt Kiryl.
Why are you being mean to Kiryl?!
なんで ｸﾘﾌﾄにｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝいくんだよ！
You're attacking Kiryl now!!
もはやｸﾘﾌﾄに
攻撃してんでしょうが！
Whatever then.
しかたあるまい｡
｢ｸﾘﾌﾄを使うな｣で手を打とう｡
I'll settle for "no Kiryl."
You think Kiryl's a nuisance, too?!
ｵﾒｴも結局 ｸﾘﾌﾄ ｼﾞｬﾏなんかい！
ﾊﾞｶ勇者どもに任せてたら
らちが明かないｱﾙ｡
This will never end if we leave
it to the stupid heroes.
私が ﾔﾂらを引きつけるね｡
I'll go draw them out.
The rest of you head for the castle.
その間に お前たちは
城に向かうｱﾙ｡
よっ！
Kagura-chan!
神楽ちゃ～ん！
あの子が いちばんの勇者だよ!!
She's the real hero here!
ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ男前なんですけど！
That was damn ballsy!
Way cooler than some
other people I know!
どっかの誰かさんたちより
全然かっこいいんですけど！
Stop wasting time!
もたもたすんな！
ﾁｬﾝｽは今しかねえ！
This is our only chance!
いくぜ!!
Let's go!
待て～い！
Wait!
ぐおっ！
先陣は勇者の指定席｡
The lead position is reserved
for the hero!
たま様を救う勇者は このｵﾚだ!!
I am the hero who will save Lady Tama!
何しやがんだ このｺｽﾌﾟﾚ勇者が！
What do you think you're
doing, Mr. Cosplay Hero?
ﾃﾒｴみてえなｲｶﾚﾎﾟﾝﾁに
率いられてたら➡
The party will be wiped out with
a psycho like you in the lead!
ﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰは全滅だ｡ このｵﾚが！
I'll do it!
うわっ！ あっ…｡
[Note: In Dragon Quest III a woman in Ashalam town
gives a "Puff-puff" (wiggles her boobs) service.]
A Jester should be getting
a puff-puff in Ashalam!
遊び人は ｱｯｻﾗｰﾑで ぱふぱふに
いそしんでいろと言ってるんだ｡
I am the leader of this party!
このﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰのﾘｰﾀﾞｰは このｵﾚだ！
ふざけんな！
ﾛﾄの勇者は引っ込んでろ｡
Don't mess with me!
[Note: Main character from the first
three Dragon Quest games.]
Loto, the hero, should get lost!
This is the age of the Heavenly Hero!
[Note: Main character for Dragon
Quest IV, V and VI.]
これからは
天空の勇者の時代なんだよ！
Hey!
ちょっと！
何やってんですか２人とも！
What are the two of you doing?!
We don't have time for this!
んなこと やってる場合ですか！
Did you just cast Defeat?!
今 ｢ｻﾞﾗｷ｣っつった？
｢ｻﾞﾗｷ｣っつったよね？
You just cast Defeat, didn't you?! Hey!
なんだよ あの２人…｡
What's wrong with the two of them?
まったく同じ顔してるのに
まったく合わないよ｡
They have the exact same face
yet they can't get along at all.
たまさん ﾎﾝﾄに あの人
銀さんがﾓﾃﾞﾙなんですか!?
Tama-san, was that person
really based on Gin-san?
相性最悪ですよ｡
最強のｺﾝﾋﾞどころか➡
They hate each other's guts.
Forget about being the strongest combo!
最悪のｺﾝﾋﾞですよ あの人ら！
They're the worst possible combo!
While cake and ramen both taste good,
combining them into cake ramen
will ruin the dish,
leaving you with something that
tastes absolutely horrible.
I may have made a terrible
miscalculation.
なに その頭悪い計算!?
That's a fatal error!
ｱﾝﾀ そんな浅はかな計算で
２人を会わせたんですか!?
You brought the two of them together
without even thinking it through?!
やばっ！ 敵に気づかれた！
Crap! The enemy spotted us!
Quick! Run away!
早く逃げて！ 銀さん 白血球王!!
Gin-san!
Leukocyte King!
おのれは！
雑菌だらけの手で➡
Do not touch me with your
virus-infested hands!
ｵﾚに気安く
触るな～っ!!
[Domestos]
[Note: A toilet-bowl cleanser.]
Domestos!
ぐわ～っ！
ｸｯ ｸｯ ｸｯ ｸｯ…｡
その程度か 勇者様の実力は…｡
Is that all a hero can do?
こんなもんじゃ ｶﾝﾀﾞﾀはおろか
ｽﾗｲﾑにも勝てやしねえ｡
Forget Kandar...
[Note: Boss from Dragon Quest III.]
You can't even defeat a single slime.
[Note: Slime is the weakest
monster in Dragon Quest.]
Now it's my turn!
今度は… ｵﾚの番だ!!
くらいやがれ～っ！
Take this!
[Magiclean]
[Note: A line of all-purpose cleaning products.]
Magiclean!
ﾌｯ… ｷｻﾏこそ この程度か｡
Is that all you're capable of?
こんなものじゃ ｽﾗｲﾑはおろか➡
Forget slimes...
朝お母さんが起こしにきたら
すでに ただの屍だ｡
Your mother will come to wake
you up in the morning,
and you'll already be a corpse.
勇者の力を見よ！
Behold the power of the hero!
[Ariel]
[Note: A laundry detergent.]
ﾌﾝ… きかねえな！
Can't touch me!
[Charmy Green]
[Note: A dishwashing detergent.]
まだ… まだ！
Not yet...
[Febreze]
[Note: An odor eliminator.]
Not yet!
What?!
なにを！
[Family Fresh]
[Note: A dishwashing detergent.]
What are you trying to hit?!
どこを狙っている！
[Dove]
[Note: Refers to Dove brand soap.]
Now for the finish!
ｺｲﾂで ｼﾒだ！
[Mama Lemon]
[Note: A dishwashing detergent.]
ｷﾞｬ～ｯ!! 何やってんだｱｲﾂら！
What are they doing?!
もう ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬだ！
This is crazy!
(たま)いえ 見てください｡
No, look.
The army of viruses are being
wiped out by their fighting.
２人のｹﾝｶに巻き込まれ
ｳｲﾙｽ軍が次々に消滅していきます｡
I didn't make a mistake.
やはり私の計算は
間違っていませんでした｡
あの２人こそ 最強の…｡
Those two are the strongest...
あっ… あれは!?
That's...
２人の技が混ざり合ってる！
Their attacks are melding...
あれは… あの光は！
This is...
That light is...
[Kamikaze]
["Super explosion caused by a mixture of light and dark power. Burn away the enemy, your own party and everything. It's very dangerous so please don't aim at people. Only use this in wide open spaces. Do Not Eat."]
[Note: Parody of warning labels.]
(源外)ん!?
おいおい… 大丈夫か？ ｱｲﾂら｡
Hey now.
Are those guys okay?
何が最強の２人だよ…｡
Who's the strongest duo again?
完全に この２人…
混ぜるな危険ですよ｡
Those two are obviously
not meant to be mixed together.
[Note: Parody of warning label on detergents.]
あぁ…｡
会わせたのが間違いだったｱﾙ｡
It was a mistake to pair them together.
ﾄﾞｯﾍﾟﾙｹﾞﾝｶﾞｰは出会ったら死ぬ
っていうｱﾙからな｡
You know how they say you'll die
if you run into your doppelganger.
このままじゃ 私たちも道連れね｡
At this rate, they'll get
the rest of us killed.
But they were able to do significant
damage to the virus army
and we have managed
to infiltrate the castle.
It's as I planned.
ｳｿつけ！
Liar!
魔王を前に ＨＰ ＭＰ
１ｹﾀみたいなもんですよ！
This is like reaching the boss with
your HP and MP in single digits!
The window is all red!
ｳｲﾝﾄﾞｳ真っ赤ですよ！
どうすんですか これ!!
What are we supposed to do?!
心配するな｡
最近のﾗｽﾎﾞｽはな 決戦前に…｡
Don't worry.
Many of the recent final bosses,
right before the final battle...
((全力でくるがいい｡
ｼﾞﾜｼﾞﾜと なぶり殺してくれる))
Show me everything you've got.
I'll kill you slowly.
などと言い ＨＰ ＭＰを
全回復してくれる者も多い｡
...say stuff like that.
Often restoring all your HP and MP.
そこに賭けよう｡
なんで ﾗｽﾎﾞｽに依存してんだ！
We'll count on that.
Why are you depending
on the final boss?!
ﾊｧｰ｡
言っとくけど
これはｹﾞｰﾑじゃないんですよ！
Just to be clear, this isn't a game.
ｾｰﾌﾞﾃﾞｰﾀも
復活の呪文もないんです！
There aren't any save points
or resurrection spells.
死んだら一巻の終わりなんです！
Die once and it's over.
頼むから
もうｹﾝｶしないでくださいよ！
Could you please stop fighting?
This isn't the time to be
hurting one another.
命削り合ってる場合じゃ
ないんですから！
ﾌﾝ そんなに命が惜しいか…｡
ならば さっさと帰れ！
Are you scared of dying?
Go ahead and turn tail and go home.
最初から言っているはずだ｡
ｵﾚ１人で十分だと…｡
As I said in the beginning,
I can handle this myself.
お前！
Hey!
なんでそんなに
ﾂﾝｹﾝ ﾂﾝｹﾝするｱﾙか？
Why do you have to be so abrasive?
銀ちゃんとお前… いや
私たちは分身みたいなものｱﾙ！
Gin-chan and you...
No, we're all the same.
見た目だけじゃない➡
It isn't just your appearance.
All of us have been protecting Tama
on the outside and the inside.
たまを内側と外側で護ってきた
同じ仲間ね！
なのに なんで
協力しようとしないｱﾙか？
Why do you refuse to cooperate?
Don't you care if Tama breaks down?!
たまが壊れてもいいｱﾙか!?
だから帰れと言っているんだ!!
That's why I'm telling you to leave!
ｷｻﾏらは たま様を救うために
ここにやってきた｡
You all came here to save Lady Tama.
たしかに たま様を
大切に思っているのだろう｡
I know you all care deeply
for Lady Tama.
But because you feel that way...
だが そんなｷｻﾏらだからこそ➡
Because you are willing to
risk your lives for a robot,
からくりのために そこまでできる
ｷｻﾏらだからこそ➡
他にもあるはずだ… 護るものが！
it means there are also other things
you strive to protect.
外にももっと…
たくさんあるはずだ｡
Things and people on the outside...
ｵﾚは違う…｡
I'm different.
ｵﾚは たま様を
護るためだけにつくられた｡
I was made for the sole purpose
of protecting Lady Tama.
ｵﾚの生きる目的は
たま様を護ることだけだ｡
I live to protect Lady Tama.
たま様以外… どうなろうと
知ったことじゃない｡
I don't care about what happens
to anyone besides Lady Tama.
I have no interest in anyone
but Lady Tama.
たま様以外のものに
何も興味はありはしない！
ぐわぁ～！
たま様以外に興味あった～！
Looks like you're interested in something
else besides Lady Tama!
なに欲出して 安いﾌﾞｰﾋﾞｰﾄﾗｯﾌﾟに
引っ掛かってるｱﾙか｡
Why are you getting greedy and falling
for such a cheap booby trap?
わ… わかっただろう…｡
D-Do you understand now?
たま様を護るのは
ｵﾚ１人で十分なんだ｡
I'll have no trouble protecting
Lady Tama by myself.
It sure doesn't look that way.
全然 十分じゃないんですけど｡
頼りなくてしかたないんですけど｡
You look hopelessly unreliable!
Idiot!
ｷｻﾏらとは 覚悟も くぐってきた
修羅場の数も違うんだ｡
I-I've been through more ordeals
than the lot of you.
あ～!!
そりゃ修羅場だらけだよね｡
Your whole life must have
been an ordeal.
こんな安いﾜﾅに引っかかってたら
命いくつあっても足りないよね！
It doesn't matter how many lives you have
if you keep falling for these cheap traps.
わかったら さっさと帰れ！
いや… じゃあ離してください｡
Leave if you understand!
Uh, then let go of me.
思いっきり
人のことつかんでるんですけど！
You've got one heck of an iron grip.
Leave after you've dealt with this!
これをなんとかしたら
さっさと帰れ！ ｼﾞｬﾏ者どもが!!
Damn nuisances!
たま様を護る勇者は
ｵﾚだけで十分だ！ あぁっ！
I am the only hero needed
to protect Lady Tama!
(たま)同じでしょう？
Isn't he just like you?
He has difficulty expressing himself...
He's antagonistic...
みんな
あなたが ﾍﾞｰｽなのです｡
He's all based on you.
You see me as such a
shameless person?
お前って ｵﾚのこと
あんな恥知らずに見えてるの？
As I observed you and collected data,
he evolved into someone
more human than I was.
That is why I could not stand by
and watch him die alone.
You should be able to understand...
Why he keeps telling you to
leave so he can go alone...
なんで あなたに
反発してくるのかも…｡
Why he acts so hostile...
お前 もしかして…｡
Did you bring the two of us together so...
ｵﾚたちと ﾔﾂを会わせたのは…｡
おい！ お前 体が！
Hey! Your body's...
It appears... that the... Tapir...
have reached...
the backup system... that
created this copy...
時間が… ありません…｡
There is... no time...
最後に お願い
聞いてもらえま… すか？
Will you... listen... to my... final request?
おそらく 私の…
ｼｽﾃﾑを復旧させることは➡
It will... probably be... impossible
to... recover my... system...
もう… 不可… 能です｡
すでに 獏は
ｼｽﾃ… の奥深くまで➡
The Tapir... are already... deep... inside...
根を… 張ってしまいま… た｡
At this... rate...
彼も… 無事では… られません｡
he won't... be able... to survive...
Forget... about... me...
いい… で… す…｡
せめて… 彼だ… け… でも➡
At least try... to free... him...
from this... place...
ここから
解放させ… あげてくだ…｡
私を… ずっと 護ってく… れた➡
My fr...d... who has... protected
me... for so... long...
私の と… ち… を…｡
私の… もう一人の… 友達を➡
Protect... my oth...r... friend...
護って…｡
たまよ…｡
Tama...
悪いが その頼み 聞けねえや｡
Sorry, but I can't honor your request.
もし 野郎が
ｵﾚのよくできた分身ってんなら➡
If he really is my clone,
ﾔﾂは そんなこと
望んじゃいねえだろうぜ｡
he would never want that.
だが 死なせやしねえよ 誰も｡
And I won't let anybody die.
ﾃﾒｴのﾀﾞﾁも ｵﾚのﾀﾞﾁもな｡
Not your friends
and not mine.
Listen up!
よいか～！ ﾈｽﾞﾐ１匹
王の間に入れるでないぞ！
Do not let a single rat
into the throne room!
もうじき この世界のｼｽﾃﾑは➡
The system of this world will soon
fall into our Tapir hands!
我々獏に 完全掌握される！
それまで 獏大魔王閣下を
お護りするのだ！
Until then, we must protect
the Archfiend Tapir!
我らの勝利は目前ぞ！
Victory is within sight!
それでは ゆけ～！
Now go forth!
な… なに～っ!?
Wh-What?!
｢ゆけ｣って
そっちの意味じゃないよ｡
That wasn't what I meant
when I said "go"!
そっちの ｢逝け｣じゃないよ！
おい 戻ってこい お前ら！
I didn't mean for you to go and die!
Hey! Come back, guys!
Yo.
よう｡
一度 聞いてみたかったんだ｡
I've always wanted to ask something.
魔王っつうのはよ➡
How does the Archfiend feel when
a level 99 Hero comes for him?
ﾚﾍﾞﾙ99の勇者が
攻め込んできたとき➡
どういう気分なんだ？
ｹﾂまくって 逃げてえ気分なのか➡
Does he feel like turning
tail and running?
それとも 地道に自分も
ﾚﾍﾞﾙ上げようとか思うのか？
Or does he try leveling himself up?
だったら
西の毛細血管洞窟が ｵｽｽﾒだ｡
If that's the case, I would recommend
the Capillary Caves to the west.
はぐれﾒﾀﾙｳｲﾙｽが出やすいぞ｡
There's a high chance you'll run
into Liquid Metal Slimes viruses.
[Note: A Dragon Quest monster.]
まぁ ﾚﾍﾞﾙなど
いくら上げても ﾑﾀﾞだがな｡
In the end, it doesn't matter
how many levels you gain.
なんせｵﾚたち 99×２➡
'Cause when you multiply 99 by
2, you get a level 198 Hero.
ﾚﾍﾞﾙ198の勇者だから｡
ｵﾚは 100だけどね｡
ｵﾚも実は 101だけど｡
Except I'm level 100.
I'm actually level 101.
いや ｵﾚ ﾎﾝﾄは 103だけど｡
No, I'm actually level 103.
ﾊﾊﾊ… すでに この世界は➡
This world has already fallen under
the absolute control of the Tapir.
我ら 獏の手によって
完全に掌握された｡
You cannot change anything.
もう 何も変えることなど
できはせぬ｡
すべては 終わったのだ｡
It's all over.
Can you not comprehend that?
そなたらには
まだ それがわからぬか｡
うっ うぅ… うわぁ～！
終わってなどいない｡
It's not over.
まだ 最後のｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰが
残っている｡
One last security measure remains.
このｵﾚが この白血球王が
いる限り➡
As long as I, the Leukocyte
King, am still here,
すべてのｼｽﾃﾑが止まろうと
この世界は 終わらない｡
this world will continue to exist after all
the systems have been knocked out!
たま様は ｵﾚが護る！
I will protect Lady Tama!
ﾌﾌﾌ… 我を倒し➡
You truly believe you can defeat
me and save this world?
この世界を救うと？
そんなことが 本気でできると？
白血球王 異界より
何人勇者をかき集めようと➡
Leukocyte King...
No matter how many heroes you bring from
other worlds, you are powerless against me.
我の前では 無力｡
断言しよう｡
ぬしに 我を倒すことはできない｡
I guarantee it.
You cannot defeat me.
倒すことはおろか
傷つけることも叶わん！
You cannot even harm me,
let alone defeat me!
今までずっと 世界を護り➡
Because you have fought to protect
this world for so long...
戦い続けてきた
ぬしだからこそ➡
誰よりも この世界を
愛している ぬしだからこそ➡
Because you love this world
more than anyone else...
我には 勝てぬ｡
You cannot defeat me.
あ あれは…｡
Th-That's...
ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな… あれは…➡
I-Impossible...
It's...
たま様！
Lady Tama!
な な… なんで!?
Wh-Wh-
What the...?!
どうして たまさんが
こんなところに!?
Why is Tama-san here?!
どうして たまさんが魔王に!?
Why is Tama-san the Archfiend?!
D-Damn you!
ｷｻﾏ！ たま様に姿を変え➡
You've assumed Lady Tama's
appearance to confuse me!
ｵﾚの動揺を誘うつもりか！
そんな安い手に ｵﾚが
かかるか～！
I won't fall for such a cheap trick!
うっ！
うっ うぅ…｡
Leukocyte King!
白血球王！
I-I can't control my body...
か 体が… 言うことをきかん｡
I can't get near him...
これ以上 ﾔﾂに近づけん｡
言ったはずだ｡
As I said...
この世界のｼｽﾃﾑは
すでに 我々が掌握したと｡
The systems of this world
are under our control.
化身などではない｡
This is no disguise.
これが 我の姿｡
This is my true form.
This body now belongs to me.
もはや この体は 我のものなのだ｡
ぬしが今 戦いを挑もうと
しているのは➡
You are trying to fight against
今まで ぬしが護り続けてきた
それ そのものなのだ｡
the person you have been protecting.
この世界を護るために
つくられたぬしが➡
As one who was created
to protect this world,
我に 歯向かえるはずもない｡
you cannot defy me.
体が ﾔﾂを たま様と認識し➡
So my body recognizes
you as Lady Tama
攻撃するのを
拒絶しているというのか!?
and refuses to attack?
ﾊﾞｶな… そんなことが｡
Impossible...
How could this...?
すべては もう終わったと
言ったはずだ｡
As I said, it's all over.
我を倒すことは すなわち➡
Defeating me will destroy this world.
この世界を滅ぼすことと同じ｡
ぬしらが護るものなど
もう 何もありはせぬのだ｡
There is nothing left for you to protect.
それでも 我を倒せるか？
Will you still try to defeat me?
この体を滅ぼしてもなお➡
Will you still try to destroy the virus even
if it means destroying this body?
護るものが
そなたらにあるか？
ﾌｯ… ぬしらに たまが殺せるか｡
Can you kill Tama?
ﾌﾌﾌ… ｱｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！
Firebane!!
[Note:  A spell from Dragon Quest.]
とりゃ～！
ﾍﾞｷﾞﾗﾏｯ!!
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
We are left with no options
as we face the
overwhelming power of
the Archfiend Tapir...
Our last hope lies in those two!
The next episode...
"Tama Quest IV: And Into the Legend..."
[Note: Parody of Dragon
Quest III subtitle.]
Uh, that's DQ III's subtitle.
[Tama Quest comes to its conclusion next week!]
[The power of the Archfiend Tapir
sends everyone back to dots.]
[See you next time.]